# Martha Kalisz

mskalisz3@gmail.com | 847-814-3212 | Portsmouth, NH

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Highly motivated agile developer with strong skills in communication, observation, and teamwork. Keen interest and relative experience in problem solving and object-oriented programming. A compassionate professional skilled at establishing and maintaining rapport for effective systematic problem solving and troubleshooting. Flexible learner skilled in adapting to novel situations.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina School of Medicine: Doctor of Physical Therapy - Chapel Hill, NC 2015-2018 University of Wisconsin School of Education: Bachelor of Science - Madison, WI 2011-2015 University of Minnesota's Learning Abroad Center: Fundación Ortega y Gasset - Toledo, ES Fall 2013 - International studies experience. Physical therapy intern, cultivated relationships, advanced Spanish language skills, created a blog.

#### LICENSURE AND CERTIFICATION

November 2021 Pluralsight

Self-guided study in Agile, Scaling Agile, Kanban, Scrum development with JIRA, Java, Spring Boot coursework

**Launch School Core Curriculum** February 2021 – Present

Self-guided study focusing on computer science fundamentals in Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git and problem-solving methodologies.

**Udacity Front End Nanodegree** February 2021

Self-guided study focusing on front-end software engineering, resulting in four custom projects.

Licensed Physical Therapist - New Hampshire

**CPR/AED for the Professional Rescuer** September 2021

October 2018 - Present

#### **TECHNICAL TOOLS**

Ruby, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Spring Boot, Git, GitHub, Node.js, Webpack, SASS, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office, Google Apps, and more

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Exeter Hospital Pediatric Rehabilitation, Epping, NH

September 2019 - Present

- Managed pediatric patients with multidisciplinary needs on a large pediatric team, requiring excellent teamwork and communication. Navigated COVID 19 pandemic, requiring constant flexibility and troubleshooting. Mentored children and young adults. Navigated Meditech systems.

# Elliot Hospital Rehabilitation, Londonderry NH

November 2018 - 2019

- Managed patients with diverse diagnoses including post-op, deconditioning, and a variety of musculoskeletal disorders while working closely with MDs and PAs in order to coordinate patient care. Supervised PT aides, students. Advocated for mentorship. Navigated Epic systems.

# UNC Children's Hospital, Chapel Hill NC

Summer 2018

- 12-week acute pediatrics. NICU, PICU, step-down. Augmented functional mobility using numerous facilitation techniques. Collaborated with hospital physicians and staff to coordinate discharge plans. Navigated Epic systems.

## UNC Physical Therapy, Hillsborough NC - Integrated Clinical Experience

Fall 2017

- Elective 1-credit course, outpatient orthopedic, evaluated and treated variety of ages with musculoskeletal conditions. Navigated Epic Systems.

# **Carolinas Medical Center Northeast, Concord NC**

Summer 2017

- 8-week outpatient pediatric rotation. Advocate for patients with various diagnoses. Casting for toe walking. Executed in-service. Navigated Cerner Systems.

#### Vidant Medical Center, Greenville NC

Summer 2017

- 8-week acute, neuromuscular rotation. Managed neurology & bariatric/gastric surgery. Observed neurosurgery. Navigated Epic Systems.

#### New Hanover Regional Medical Center, Wilmington NC

Summer 2016

- 8-week outpatient orthopedic rotation with dry needling, IASTM. Presented in-service. Observed 3 orthopedic surgeries. Navigated Epic Systems.

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

## Constraint-Induced Movement Therapy Camp, Chapel Hill NC

Summer 2018

- 8-day camp. Lead therapeutic activities for children with hemiplegia based on NDT, designed creative treatments and home exercise programs.

# **Capstone Project, UNC DPT Program**

Spring 2018

- Produced and improved doctorate-level coursework focusing on pediatric orthotics for the 3rd year Child and Family Assessment Elective.

# Musculoskeletal Teaching Scholar, UNC DPT Program

Spring 2018

- Elective 2-credit course, enhanced curriculum, lectured for, and assisted with lab portions of Musculoskeletal coursework.

# **Child and Family Assessment Elective Course**

Fall 2017

- Elective 3-credit course. Expanded skills and knowledge of pediatric evaluation, treatment, and current trends and research.

# **Student Physical Therapy Association Leadership**

Fall 2015-Summer 2018

- Vice President from spring of 2016 through summer of 2017. Organized planning of events such as APTA's Advocacy Dinner.

American Physical Therapy Association NEXT Conference, Nashville TN

Summer 2016 Summer 2015-Present

American Physical Therapy Association: NC and NH Chapters; Academy of Pediatric Physical Therapy **UNC Physical Therapy Student Advisory Board** 

Fall 2015-Summer 2018

## **RELATED EXPERIENCE**

#### Office Assistant, University of North Carolina Chapel Hill Division of Physical Therapy

Summer 2016-Spring 2018

- Energized Drs. Lewek and McCarty by assisting with research and office tasks; operated, gathered data, organized UNC's Stroke Research Registry.
- Facilitated clinic organization including insurance, chart management, and patient scheduling via in-person, phone, and email contacts.

## Campus Visit Specialist, Campus and Visitor Relations, Madison, WI

Summer 2013-2015

- Managed multiple accounts and collaborated with Campus Partners to plan specialty visits and tours for approx. 30,000 guests per year.

# Research Assistant, Dr. Eldridge's Pediatric Cardiopulmonary Lab, UW Hospital, Madison, WI

Summer 2014-Spring 2015

- Contributed to the execution of translational studies and data analysis handling bronchopulmonary dysplasia and right ventricle interactions.